Iason Somarakis

Greece



jason_somarakis@protonmail.com



linkedin.com/in/iason-somarakis-493474100

Summary

lason Somarakis works as a senior security engineer, focusing on research, development and application of security solutions. With experience in penetration testing methodologies and tools, virtualization and containerization means and machine learning algorithms for enhanced proactive and reactive security mechanisms. Furthermore, he has an up to date view of the technological landscape and a diverse toolkit of programming languages, networking, and infrastructure as a code frameworks.

lason's research interests involve different types of security assessments, specifically emulation technologies for cyber range training and offensive technologies for penetration testing and threat emulation.

Last but not least, his personal interests include capture the flag activities, privacy related topics, cryptocurrencies, and reading novels.

Experience

Senior Security Engineer

Sphynx Technology Solutions

Aug 2021 - Present (5 months +)

Primarily working on:

Developing the emulation mechanisms and training content for SPHYNX's Cyber Range capabilities.

Developing and integrating open source tools for SPHYNX's Penetration Testing capabilities.

Additionally leading:

- A cyber range training platform for medical organisations and systems security (AERAS)
- Resilient Transport Infrastructure to Extreme Events (RESIST)

Security Engineer

Sphynx Technology Solutions

Jan 2020 - Aug 2021 (1 year 8 months)

Primarily working on:

- Developing the emulation mechanisms and training content for SPHYNX's Cyber Range capabilities.
- Developing and integrating open source tools for SPHYNX's Penetration Testing capabilities.

Leading SPHYNX's efforts on the following HORIZON2020 Projects:

- HOLOBALANCE: HOLOgrams for personalised virtual coaching and motivation in an ageing population with BALANCE disorders
- RESIST: Resilient Transport Infrastructure to Extreme Events

In addition working on the following HORIZON2020 Projects:

- THREAT ARREST: Cyber Security Threats and Threat Actors Training - Assurance Driven, Multi Layer, End-to-End Simulation and Training

Software Engineer

Sphynx Technology Solutions

Apr 2018 - Jan 2020 (1 year 10 months)

Primarily working on:

- Developing and integrating open source tools for SPHYNX's Penetration Testing capabilities. Leading SPHYNX's efforts on the following HORIZON2020 Projects:
- RESIST: Resilient Transport Infrastructure to Extreme Event
- HOLOBALANCE: HOLOgrams for personalised virtual coaching and motivation in an ageing population with BALANCE disorders

Additionally working on the following HORIZON2020 Projects:

- SEMIOTICS: Smart End-To-End Massive lot Interoperability Connectivity and Security
- THREAT ARREST: Cyber Security Threats and Threat Actors Training Assurance Driven, Multi Layer, End-to-End Simulation and Training

【 IT Support Technician

Curvature

Apr 2016 - Dec 2016 (9 months)

Job Summary:

This position assists local and remote staff with technical support of desktop computers, laptops, applications, and related technology. Support includes specification, installation, and testing of computer systems and peripherals within established standards and guidelines. Activities require interaction with application software and operating systems to diagnose and resolve problems. The position utilizes one-on-one consultancy to end users. The position's responsibilities require independent analyses, communication and problem solving. Work is performed with little supervision and requires initiative and judgment.

Primary Roles and Responsibilities:

- * Assist staff with the installation, configuration, and ongoing usability of desktop computers, peripheral equipment and software within established standards and guidelines.
- * Assist in the design and deployment of a standard OS and Software images
- * Works with vendor support contacts to resolve technical problems with desktop computing equipment and software.
- * Manages Help Desk request queue (Ticketing System, Knowledgebase, and Asset Management).
- * Trains and orients staff on use of hardware and software.
- * Performs upgrades on systems to ensure longevity.
- * Assists in maintaining Voice related services
- * Uphold all aspects of Curvature's Information Security Management systems.

【 IT Support /Network administrator Trainee

Curvature

Oct 2015 - Apr 2016 (7 months)

Network Administration and Desktop Support

■ Technician's assistant / IT support

Ipekat IKE

Jun 2013 - 2015 (2 years 7 months)

Education

City, University of London

PhD, Computer and Information Systems Security/Information Assurance 2019 - 2023

Asset and Threat Emulation for Cybersecurity Training at School of Mathematics, Computer Sciences & Engineering

Technological Educational Institute of Crete

Computer Software Engineering

2010 - 2018

Worked on several projects mainly on Python, JAVA, C++, Matlab.

Licenses & Certifications



EU Scholarship - Android Development for Beginners - Udacity

Neural Networks and Deep Learning - Coursera

AX7EC2SQX9KD

The Ultimate Ethical Hacking Course 2017 - Udemy UC-XRNM4HIJ

IDS/IPS - Cybrary SC-c61f1a18c3-a3b75

- Incident Handling Training Cource at NIS 2018 ENISA-FORTH
- Penetration Testing and Ethical Hacking Cybrary C-c61f1a18c3-a2f5b1
- Python for Security Professionals Cybrary C-c61f1a18c3-a9ae436
- Entry Level Training of Cyber-MAR project CyberMAR

Offensive Pentesting Learning Path - TryHackMe

THM-T8YUMV0S6S

Skills

Software Development • Penetration Testing • Virtualization • Containerization • Research • Vagrant (Software) • Ansible • Docker Products • VirtualBox • Python (Programming Language)